# PATRICK MUTH

Brooklyn, NY | 603-512-7131 | patrickmuth.com | patrick.muth@gmail.com

Creative problem solver with a proven track record of designing highly usable, user-centered experiences. Passion for combining creativity and technology to make people's lives better.

#### **SKILLS**

Design, iterate and refine UX concepts through research, interviews, workshops, storyboards, user flows, wireframes, prototyping & user testing. Effectively communicate user experience designs to team members, stakeholders, and present to clients.

Deep knowledge and experience in Figma, Sketch, Framer and Adobe CC

Experience prototyping a variety of interactive projects, including web/mobile, experiential & physical computing.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Family Break/Freelance Senior UX Designer

February 2023 to Present

- Provided in-home care for my mother while she underwent treatment related to a medical condition.
- Worked remotely as a Freelance Senior UX Designer performing duties similar to previous experience.

#### Service & Interaction Designer, Accenture Song

New York, NY, September 2021 to November 2022

- Designed an interactive prototype for a web-based proprietary B2B transformation tool, conducting stakeholder interviews and a competitor analysis to determine how best to track daily and monthly data and measure that against a project's long-term goals.
- Created a vision plan for modernizing and digitizing the in-person experience for a global non-profit youth education program, using stakeholder interviews and competitor research to determine project requirements.

#### Senior Experience Designer (Contract), Publicis Sapient

New York, NY, July 2020 to September 2021

• Led user experience for the redesign of a customer-facing user management portal for the business division of a leading telecommunications company. Combined workflows for multiple products into a single, unified experience for creating and managing users. Designed user flows, wireframes and additional documentation for creating and managing user profiles and permissions, as well as a user directory.

#### Senior UX Designer (Contract), AKQA

New York, NY, December 2019 to April 2020

- Created user flows and preliminary wireframes for a proof of concept for a new patient scheduling tool for a major US hospital, working with client stakeholders and a technical team to determine project requirements
- Developed information architecture and wireframes for a design system repo for the hospital's new digital component library

## Senior Interaction Designer (Contract), Frog Design

Brooklyn, NY, October 2019 to December 2019

 Developed wireframes, information architecture and interactive prototypes (Framer) for the digital launch of a new investment platform for a major American investment group

## UX Designer (Contract), Big Spaceship

Brooklyn, NY, September 2019 to October 2019

 Developed wireframes, user flows & competitive analyses for a national satellite radio providers website redesign, focusing on site search and customer account administration

## Senior UX Designer (Contract), Valtech

New York, NY, April 2019 to May 2019

- Led user experience on the development of a digital innovation focused concept store for a national makeup brand, creating concepts for new digital interaction for both the in-store and online experience
- Conducted in-person interviews with customers and store employees to develop insights and user journeys based on their shopping behavior

## **UX Designer, Patients & Purpose**

New York, NY, November 2016 to October 2018

- Created wireframes, user flows and functional specs for projects with multinational pharmaceutical companies including desktop and mobile web sites and mobile apps
- Participated in the execution of usability studies, creating wireframes, clickable prototypes and user interview questions
- Spearheaded ongoing research on new approaches and ideas such as chatbots, progressive registration and voice user interactions for integration into new and ongoing work streams

## Junior UX Designer, Bossa Digital

New York, NY, August 2013 to September 2016

- Designed responsive web wireframes and user flows for clients such as General Mills, Google & Target, as well as a Cannes Lion winning campaign for Coke Zero
- Created interactive prototypes of mobile designs for clients such as McDonalds, Coke Zero
  & Airbnb using Framer, InVision & Pixate

# **EDUCATION**

**New York University,** Masters in Interactive Telecommunications (ITP) **Providence College,** B.S. in Marketing